<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>get sh*t done - the blog</title>
<link>https://blog.frieder-rodewald.de/</link>
<atom:link href="https://blog.frieder-rodewald.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>a project aimed to get sh*t done</description>
<generator>quarto-1.4.466</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Getting started writing - my first PhD paper</title>
  <dc:creator>Frieder Rodewald</dc:creator>
  <link>https://blog.frieder-rodewald.de/posts/first_phd_paper.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="lets-get-started" class="level1">
<h1>Let’s Get Started</h1>
<p>Here comes the first sentence. And a second one. I’m just typing something that I think would sound good. Does it? I actually have no idea where to start; my head seems kind of empty today. Now, thinking about it, What do I even want to write about? What was my topic again? Fuck, I forgot. How can this be? I have already written a whole proposal about it. Anyway, keep calm and start from the top. I am interested in privacy, specifically, how we can measure it. For starters, I want to know how we can know what privacy behavior really is and how we can measure it. The last sentence does not really make sense. Ok, let’s try to start again. How does self-reported online privacy behavior compare to self-reported privacy behavior? No, fucked it up again - you just wrote two times the same stuff. Let’s start differently. Why do I want to use data donation? Because it’s an awesome way to get to really good behavioral data. Self-reports cannot do the same. Self-reported privacy behavior falls prey to a multitude of biases, e.g., recall bias or desirability biases. People just don’t really know what they do online. Or at least they don’t remember that information when they are asked about it in a different setting - so when they are not online. On a different note, they do not even know what kind of content they consumed or pushed five minutes after scrolling, liking, and commenting for an hour and a half. Maybe some remember, but most probably do not. I at least don’t, and I hate this. In comes data donation to the rescue. Compared to other approaches, it actually allows me to see what people do online without having to rely on their self-reports. While I could also use some kind of tracking, data donation seems to be better suited for this kind of behavior as participants do not have to go through the hussle of installing an app or some browser plugin. And then they know that they are being tracked, which is not ideal. And still, especially if we are interested in (privacy) settings, trackers or even APIs for that matter cannot give us the needed information. But data donation can. And that’s why I want to use it.</p>
<div class="callout callout-style-default callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Note
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>[And at this point did I start to write a first draft of an introduction to my first PhD paper :)]</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="for-context---what-is-this" class="level1">
<h1>For Context - What is this?</h1>
<p>I try to trick myself when I have to write something, but I do not feel like writing. This method works best for me. I just start typing anything that comes to mind. It does not necessarily concern the research question or the part I must write. I write. Eventually, I got to think more about the topic. Normally, after 20 minutes or more, I am writing and will start the work I must do. By that point, I will have already written some stuff; some might be relevant, some not.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>personal</category>
  <category>writing</category>
  <guid>https://blog.frieder-rodewald.de/posts/first_phd_paper.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>My first conference</title>
  <dc:creator>Frieder Rodewald</dc:creator>
  <link>https://blog.frieder-rodewald.de/posts/first_conference.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="prologe" class="level1">
<h1>Prologe</h1>
<p>I had heard about the Transforming Care Conference already in November last year but never really thought about attending right before the deadline for abstract submission in January. As I was still in my peak phase of writing together my thesis’ findings, I did not have much time to spend on the abstract and just wrote down what I had in mind. Coming as a surprise to me, it worked. My paper actually was accepted and would go to England to my first academic conference.</p>
</section>
<section id="day-1---monday" class="level1">
<h1>Day 1 - Monday</h1>
<p>Just got up, had breakfast and am now about to leave for the conference. This is my first one ever. Kinda excited but I think I will be fine. I am thinking about what to wear, probably will settle for semi-formal - can never go wrong with that. I finished by presentation yesterday after arriving in Sheffield by train, it was quite a nice trip here. Had a pint in a pub, enjoyed people talking in their most lovely British dialect (or the local dialect, I actually have no idea, but it sounds fabulous :). Hoping to meet some nice people and figure out, how such conferences work - that’s the reason I’m actually here. So, I just came back. What a day. I am exhausted but it was actually quite nice. After I got there I stood around for a minute and then just went to the first person I saw also sitting alone. And we started talking. He was really kind, we had lunch together and from there on I just snowballed my way through new connections. There are really lovely people attending the conference. Everyone is really open and as eager to get to know people around them. I did not feel a special need to network, so we just chatted and got to know each other and our interests. I attended a really thought-provoking (used quite often there) panel were we stayed to talk for a bit. In the evening, there was an early career get-together which I enjoyed quite a lot. Actually talking to people in their PhDs is a nice experience and really shows how they too, as normal people, have and had their problems and dealt with them. It stays true. Talking to others helps so much.</p>
</section>
<section id="day-2---tuesday" class="level1">
<h1>Day 2 - Tuesday</h1>
<p>I slept quite well, but still a bit exhausted. I am not too stressed, went through my presentation again yesterday evening and now feel prepared. I am most afraid of the questions I get, so I think I might read through my thesis, the basis for my paper, again to recall all the information. That’s most probably unnecessary, but i will feel better after reading it. I slept too long, so there is not real time to have breakfast. Anyhow, I am not really into breakfasts too, so that’s fine. It was awesome. I really enjoyed today. Though it was a long day. First, had one ok-isch and one really interesting panel - again about care and surveillance. Then I felt quite tired and thought about going back to the hotel for a nap after lunch. However, I met cool people while queuing and we talked for so long. Surprisingly, this gave me quite some energy back, and after skimming through my thesis, I felt prepared for the presentation. And it went well. I could say what I had prepared and felt like getting the general idea of my paper across to the other researchers in the room. They had quite some questions and nice comments about it. Though I did not understand all questions immediately, I have thought about them since and what I would have responded to them. Unfortunately, the opportunity to respond is now gone, but I can use their questions in remarks anyways :) I did not join the dinner, as it was quite expensive and I did not feel like spending so much fancy money to network. Anyways, others thought so too and we headed out for some pints in a pub. This was such a cool experience to get to know them. PhD students with so much experience to learn from and ginuently lovely people. I hope to meet them again in the future. Anyways, I am quite exhausted now…</p>
</section>
<section id="day-3---wednesday" class="level1">
<h1>Day 3 - Wednesday</h1>
<p>Slept to little - feel quite tired. The feeling did not go away throughout the day. The last panel session was nice, although I felt already quite full. Three days of conference are quite a thing. Two people actually came to me and told me that that found my presentation quite interesting - couldn’t ask for a better boost of energy :D After lunch, I took the train to London and then over the channel home. I am thinking out publishing this short diary online, maybe over the weekend - let’s see.</p>
</section>
<section id="day-x---the-week-after" class="level1">
<h1>Day X - The week after</h1>
<p>Still haven’t published the blog article. Maybe need to to it today evening or tomorrow. tbs</p>
</section>
<section id="day-y---still-months-later" class="level1">
<h1>Day Y - Still months later</h1>
<p>I do not know what held me back, but better late then never - today I publish this. For the future, I really have to just put the stuff I write actually online. It does not seem that difficult…but it is :D</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>personal</category>
  <guid>https://blog.frieder-rodewald.de/posts/first_conference.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://blog.frieder-rodewald.de/posts/image.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
